Contact

nzayangeta4149@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sharon-nzayaaa741518a (LinkedIn) github.com/dashboard (Other)

Top Skills

Data Science

Machine Learning and Al

Programming

Languages

Kiswahili (Full Professional) English (Full Professional) French (Limited Working)

Certifications

SQL Database
Python 3 Programming

Honors-Awards

2nd Place Winner

Sharon Nzaya

Founder of Oona Data Kenya

Summary

I'm a Data Scientist with months of experience using statistical methods and analysis to solve business problems. I have always been a numbers person, with exceptional mathematics and computer skills. The power to transform lives lies within the knowledge of big data that is why I joined Moringa School where I specialized in SQL, model building in Python, and R. I am well versed with Tableau for data visualization, Machine Learning Algorithms such as Neural Networks, Natural Language Processing, Supervised and Unsupervised models.

Experience

Oona Data Founder and CEO February 2020 - Present (7 months) Nairobi, Kenya

We are a data science firm delivering Al-powered software and technical solutions to companies who want to leverage data and machine learning algorithms for business value.

Focusing on machine learning, recommendation systems, data product design, data mining, web scraping, image processing, data visualization, AI software development, computer vision, and intelligent automation, we help businesses innovate with AI, enrich customer insights, automate processes & be more cost-efficient. This is ensured by our proprietary technologies, exceptional customer care, constant investment into talent development.

SUPA LOAF

Software Engineer February 2019 - April 2019 (3 months)

Kagundo Road

I developed information systems by designing, developing, and installing software solutions. I also determined operational feasibility by evaluating

analysis, problem definition, requirements, solution development, and proposed solutions.

I documented and demonstrated solutions by developing the documentation, flowcharts, layouts, diagrams, charts, code comments, and clear code.

I improved operations by conducting systems analysis and recommending changes in policies and procedures. I provide information by collecting, analyzing and summarizing development and service issues.

I partly worked as a Graphic Designer using GIMP and Blender Tool in 3D design and 2D animation

Education

Moringa School

Data Science, Data Science · (2019 - 2019)

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology IT Software, Computer Software Engineering · (2017 - 2019)